我也许会死
I might die.
我很可能会死
I very likely will die.
我不求活着
I'm not asking to live.
您让我赎罪了
You've given me redemption,
所以我不再惧怕死亡
and it's that which makes me no longer fear death.
我怕的
What I fear...
是无用之死
is a fruitless death.
我要求的
What I ask for...
在您给了我那么多之后
after you have given me so much...
就是使命
...is purpose.
醒醒  鸡蛋薄煎饼  格雷戈里
Wakey, wakey, eggs pancakey, Gregory.
不说声谢谢吗
No thank you?
不说声好棒吗
No "Yay!"?
这煎饼是我亲手做的
These cakes are made from scratch by yours truly.
我用了山顶寨的纯正高粱
I used genuine Hilltop sorghum.
亲自碾磨的
Milled it myself.
是吗
You -- You -- You did?
是啊
Uh-huh.
这托盘上爱意满满呢  格雷戈里
There is a lot of love on this tray, Gregory,
因为我想表达对你的爱
because I wanted to express love to you.
因为你做了正确的事
'Cause you did the right thing.
我告诉过你  如果山顶寨有什么不对劲
I told you if things started to feel hinky at the Hilltop
就来找我
to come see me.
我按你说的做了
A-And I did.
毫不犹豫
With zero hesitation.
是啊
Yes.
你按我的指示
You went to the satellite outpost
去了卫星站
as I instructed.
那真是了不起啊
Which was incredibly impressive.
你已经跟我说过了
You told me that already.
是吗
I did?
三次了
Three times.
听着  你来找我了
Listen, you came to see me.
尽管我已经离开了
And though I was already away,
去处理内乱的事
dealing with that... rank betrayal,
而你不知道
which was unknown to you...
是的  我的确不知道
Oh, indeed, it was unknown.
我的确不知道
It was, indeed, unknown.
你等了我
And you waited for me.
因为我想跟你说
'Cause I wanted to tell you about...
山顶寨  亚历山大和神之国的事
well, Hilltop and Alexandria, the Kingdom.
但你那时候在亚历山大已经知道这事了  对吧
But you were finding out at that point in Alexandria, right?
格雷戈里  你不用一遍又一遍地解释
Gregory, you don't need to explain yourself over and over again.
听我说
Hear me when I say,
我告诉你  你做了正确的事
I'm telling you, you did the right thing.
每一步都对
Every step of the way.
你为什么带我来这里
Why did you bring me here?
我带你来这里
I brought you here
是因为我们如今濒临绝境
because we now stand on the precipice of greatness.
你说你可以解决问题
You said you could solve the problem.
就是今天了  格雷戈里
Today's the day, Gregory.
你用我的爱填满肚子
You fill your belly up with my love,
然后去解决问题
and then you solve it.
好
Aye, aye.
我
Well, I, uh...
首先我想说
I'd just like to start by saying
感谢今天邀请我来
thank you for having me here today.
尼根  我就和你直说了
Negan, let me lay this down straight for you.
这些我全懂
I know how it is...
管理资源和人口
negotiating the slippery, steep terrain
是非常微妙而难以处理的事
of managing resources and the population
而且还有可怕的"未"
and the big, scary U.
你应该知道那指什么  就是"未知情况"
which you might know, it's called the unknown.
听着  我这话是认真的
Listen, I-I mean it when I say it --
尼根  我不比你更喜欢杀人
Negan, I don't like killing people any more than you do.
我喜欢杀人
I like killing people.
我...
Oh. Well, I --
我觉得重点在于杀死正确的人
I say it's about killing the right people.
你在正确的时间杀死正确的人...
So, you kill the right people at the right time...
一切都水到渠成
everything falls into place.
大家都开心
Everybody's happy.
当然其中一部分人会更开心一些
Well, some people more than others.
但是你杀了一个
But you kill one,
就能拯救上百个
and you could be saving hundreds more.
这才是我们的使命
And that is what we are all about.
我们拯救人们
We save people.
所以...
That's...
所以你们才自称"救世军"
That's why you're called the -- the Saviors.
我去抽根烟
Gonna grab a smoke.
现在吗
Now?
你不想听这些吗
You don't want to hear this?
不需要听
Don't need to.
告诉我该去哪  该做什么  我自会落实
Tell me where to go and what to do, I'll make it happen.
我们刚刚讲到哪了  格雷戈里
Where were we, Gregory?
对了...
Oh, that's right --
你刚刚在和我说你不喜欢杀人
you were telling me that you don't like to kill people,
而我说我喜欢...
and I was saying that I do --
只要情势所需
under the right circumstances.
我们...我们所处的
Well, this -- this situation
这个...这个情况
that we -- we find ourselves in,
这个...这个冲突...
this -- this conflict...
我可以把它扼杀在摇篮里
I can stop it ?before it even gets started.
我是说  就这样
I mean, here it is.
我去找我的人  告诉他们
I go to my people, and I -- I tell them
假如你们走上这条...
if -- if you're joining with this --
不正确的道路
this misled crusade,
你们就不再是山顶寨的居民了
you're no longer citizens of the Hilltop.
你们出去自生自灭吧
You're out on your asses.
你还是他们的领袖吗
You're still their guy?
他们还听你的吗  格雷戈里
They still listen to you, Gregory?
你还有权放逐他们吗
Can you exile people?
山顶寨是我的地盘
The Hilltop is my house.
我依旧是他们的领袖
I'm still the guy.
我一直是他们的领袖
I've always been the guy.
假如你还是他们的领袖
If you're still the guy,
假如你确实一直是他们的领袖
if, indeed, you have always been the guy,
那你他妈为什么会不知道那个寡妇
then why the hell didn't you know about the widow
领着一队你的人
leading an army of your people
在亚历山大偷袭了我
straight up my ass in Alexandria?
你知道我是怎么想的吗  格雷戈里
You know what I think, Gregory?
我觉得你就是根墙头草
I think you're playing both sides.
我觉得你是个虚伪的政客
I think you are a thin-dicked politician
带着那副虚伪的嘴脸两头讨好
threading the needle with your thin, thin dick.
到底听你的话是正确的选择呢
Now, is listening to you the right way to go,
还是此时此地干点别的事更正确呢
or is it the right place and time for something else?
不不  我没想那么做
No, no. Not trying to do that.
不  不...
No, not --
直到他们开始行动
I was -- wasn't aware of things
我才意识到发生了什么
until they were already in -- in motion.
我半点没有犹豫
N-No hesitation.
我从头到尾都是忠诚的
Allegiance, right there, the whole thing.
我只是...在我知道之前我一直不知情
I just -- I-I didn't know until I-I knew, you know?
格雷戈里
Gregory.
我相信你
I believe you.
现在你得让尼根相信你
Now make Negan believe you, huh?
山顶寨是我的底盘
The Hilltop is mine.
我让狐狸钻进了鸡窝
I let a fox into my hen house.
她和她的人利用了我慷慨的天性
She and her people took advantage of my generous nature.
我现在明白了  我会弥补的
I see that now, and I will fix it.
假如我们摆好阵势过去
If we go in with the right stage picture,
展示出我们强大的势力
a thick and veiny show of force
在格雷戈里发号施令时为他做后盾
surrounding Gregory when he lays down the law,
我觉得事情就能回归正轨了
I think things go back to copacetic.
假如他们不听话  我们就当场行动
If they don't, we take a flyer on the place
把所有人都杀了
and kill everyone there.
这计划是很不幸
Unfortunate play,
但其他社区会得到警告
but the other communities will get the message,
而我们能维持平衡
and we achieve equilibrium.
A计划
Plan A.
B计划
Plan B --
人是资源
People are a resource.
摆在桌面上的利益
Money on the table.
人是我们建立一切的基础
People are the foundation of what we are building here!
你他妈以为你在跟谁说话
Who the hell do you think you're talking to?
你搞错了我们是谁吗
Are you confused about who we are?
你搞错了谁是老大吗
Are you confused about who is in charge?
我们倒退了吗  西蒙
Are we backsliding, Simon?
求你告诉我  我们没倒退吧
Please, ?tell me we're not backsliding.
我们没倒退
We're not backsliding.
这是重大事件  也是紧要关头
This is a pronounced event and a fragile moment.
当然是了
Hell, yes, it is.
我们得取得全胜
We need to win it all.
A计划
Plan A
是活捉瑞克  寡妇和混球国王
is taking the Rick, the widow, and King Assface alive
以非常非常公开
and making them dead
和有效的方式处死他们
in a very, very public and instructive way.
我们要用最不人道的方式杀死正确的人
We kill the right people in the wrongest way possible,
逼他们全部看着
and we make them all watch!
该派我们的人出去吗
Should we get our people out there?
列队  扫射他们
Line 'em up, light 'em up?
不
No.
他们有土气的装甲
They got some sort of hillbilly armor.
那样只会浪费子弹
We'd just be wasting metal on metal.
火箭发射器还在库里  所以
And the RPG is stashed at the cache, so...
我们去聊聊
let's have ourselves a little chat.
西蒙  带上你的新朋友
Simon, bring your new little friend.
或许需要他讲几句
We may need him to say some words.
格雷戈里  该你上了
Gregory, you're on deck.
加里  窗口各安排三人
Gary, put three and three in the windows.
让他们别轻举妄动
Tell them to stay the hell down till we need them.
活见鬼了
Well, shit.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
妈呀
Jesus Christ.
我刚在开会
I was in a meeting.
真方便
Well, that's handy.
还有一整梭子呢
This one still has a full clip.
开枪没有任何意义
There wasn't any point in firing it.
我子弹不够多
I didn't have enough.
是啊  但你本可以抵抗到死的  娇气孩子
Yeah, but you could've gone down fighting, you big baby.
我只是逗逗你  和你打打趣
I'm just pulling your dick, breakin' your balls a little bit.
你做得很好  聪明之举
You done good. Smart play.
来扶你坐好吧
Let's get you properly on your ass.
你朋友瑞克是个混蛋
Your friend Rick is an asshole.
你才是个混蛋
You're an asshole.
是啊
Yeah.
我是
I am.
但是他会害死别人的
But he's gonna get people killed.
被你杀死
By you.
我杀了寡妇和老公和红毛
See, I killed the widow's husband and the ginger.
但我没害死他们
But I didn't get them killed.
害死他们的是你朋友瑞克
That was your boy Rick.
区别很大
Big difference.
我看到你停下救格雷戈里那个蠢货了
You know, I saw you stop for that Gregory idiot.
你在那里  你目睹了一切
You were there. ?You saw the whole thing.
你听到了他说的话
You heard his little speech.
你为什么停下救那个胡子混蛋
Why would you stop for that bearded prick?
我怕的是无用之死
What I fear is a fruitless death.
天啊  你在说笑吧
Jesus Christ. ?You got to be kiddin' me.
他出卖了你这怪人
He split on your creepy little ass.
而你生命的意义是拯救那个白痴吗
The point of your life would be saving that dickhead?
不是
That wouldn't be it.
我那样做一定有别的原因
There had to be some reason I did what I did.
或许这就是原因
Maybe this is the reason.
什么
What?
我觉得
I think...
我是来听你忏悔的
I'm here to take your confession.
《行尸走肉》
你们在化工厂的人
Your people back in the chemical plant...
你们赢了吗
Did you win?
没人赢
No one did.
他妈什么意思
The hell's that supposed to mean?
所有人都死了
Everyone's dead.
放屁
Bullshit.
没活人了吗  就剩你了
There's no one else? You're the only one?
我
Me.
国王
The King.
斧子男
The axe man.
还有个短发疯婆子
And a short-haired psycho lady.
是你们干的
You did this.
我们的人
My people...
你们的人
your people...
都死了
they're all gone.
该死
Damn.
现在
And now...
我也要死了
me, too.
我们可以等等
We can wait it out a little bit,
看我的人能否想出什么办法
see if my people can figure something out.
一件事可以确定
One thing that is sure as ass...
如果我的人认为我死了
if my people think I'm dead...
里面会死很多人的
a lot of folks are gonna die in there.
为什么
Why?
听着
Listen to me.
我没什么好忏悔的
I don't have shit to confess.
除了我偶尔会坐在你那位子上
Except maybe the fact that I rubbed one out
撸一发让自己冷静冷静
right where you're sitting just to calm down a bit.
我问你
Let me ask you something.
你为什么当神父
Why'd you become a priest?
我爱上帝  爱人们
I love God, and I love people.
想把他们联系起来
I wanted to bring them together.
帮人们度过难关
To help people through their difficult times.
帮他们克服弱点
To help them through their weaknesses.
瞧瞧
Well, look at that.
那明明是我的责任
That's my thing.
我也喜欢帮人们克服弱点
I like to help people through their weaknesses, too.
我这辈子一直在用不同的方法那样做
Been doing it one way or another my whole life.
你怎么帮人们的
How do you help people?
你知道里面的人为什么会死吗
You want to know why people are gonna start dying in there?
因为我没在那里阻止
Because I'm not there to stop it.
我们只能假设尼根已经死了
We have to assume Negan's dead.
我就是尼根
I'm Negan.
而且就我理解  这屋里的每个人都是
And as I understand it, everyone in this room is.
我知道现在大家很紧张
Now, I realize there's a lot of stress in the air,
但是确认一下
but just to clarify,
你觉得自己不是尼根吗  瑞吉娜
are you saying you're someone else, Regina?
没有
No.
很好
Good.
我们应该派栅栏小队出去
We should send the fence crew out.
再叫上几个人
Grab a few others,
-四十个工人  背靠背站着  -不
- we get 40 workers, standing back to back. - No.
让他们拿着管子出去
We get them out with pipes,
清出一条路
they clear a path...
-够一小队人走...  -行不通
- just enough for a small team... - Inadequate.
什么
What?
你说的数量行不通
The numbers you suggest aren't adequate.
按照我们周围的实时尸群密度
Given the current S.R.O. density of the herd surrounding us,
四十个工人装备近战武器  组成此阵型
40 workers armed with melee weapons in the formation you propose
几分钟内就会被包围歼灭
would be overcome, closed in on, and macked upon within a few minutes.
对  没错
Yeah. That's right.
我们用工人分散行尸注意力
We use the workers as a distraction
让一小队人穿过尸群
to get a small team past the herd.
他们可以去警告哨站
They can warn the outposts
然后带回"胖女人"
and then come back with the Fat Lady.
这个方案不仅成功机会渺茫
Add to the approach's slim chances of success,
还可能导致人心惶惶
it's likely the play would lead to widespread unrest,
在食物与燃料已趋于匮乏时
pitting the workers against the soldiers
挑起工人与士兵对立
when we're running out of food and fuel,
这会打乱原本已不牢靠的现状
upsetting our already precarious apple cart.
或许只要把你扔出去
Maybe all we need to do
就能解决一切问题呢  尤金
is put you out there, Eugene.
或许这样能激励咱们的智多星
Maybe it would motivate the answer man
想出解决方法
to come up with a solution.
瑞吉娜  他说的没错
Regina, he's right.
工人有人数优势
The workers have the numbers,
我们得拉拢他们
and we need to keep them on our side.
我们得控制住他们
We need to keep them in line.
即使我们有几个人能逃出去  甚至清空尸群
Even if we get a few of ours out and somehow clear the crowd,
他们也早在建筑四周布满狙击手
they have snipers ?all around the building.
所以现在  我们先处理另一个问题
So right now, let's deal with the other part.
这屋里的某人  得为外面的事负责
Someone in here made everything out there happen.
当我们正在针对亚历山大的反叛
We're having our little crisis-management meeting
召开危机处理会议时
about the rebellion in Alexandria,
我们三个哨站领队齐聚于此
us three outpost heads,
而他们就选在此时对我们动手
and that's when they pile this crap on us?
偏在这时候将我们封锁
That's when they cut us off?
别傻了
Come on.
他们无所不见  无所不知
They knows all and sees all.
杀人不一定要用枪
Sometimes it doesn't take a gun.
只需要一个叛徒
The right kind of rat...
动一张嘴  就能害死一帮人
can kill plenty of people with just some talk.
但死的不会是我们
But it's not gonna be us,
也不一定得是工人们
and it doesn't have to be the workers.
德怀特  你要认清现实
Dwight, you got to face reality here.
不  西蒙  我们坚守属于我们的
No, Simon, we keep what's ours,
一个也不放弃
and we don't give up a damn thing.
我们杀出重围
We get out.
我不想再听见你们俩
And I don't want to hear backbiting
说些背后伤人或是抱怨的话
or pissing or moaning from you two.
你们有意见  冲着我来
You got a problem with that, come at me.
你若不能带领救世军离开这儿  换我来
You can't lead the Saviors out of here, I will.
好的  好孩子
Yes, my boy.
很好
Yes!
而且
And...
我们会揪出害我们的那个人渣
we're gonna find that subhuman coward that did this to us,
我们要当着所有人面
and we're gonna kill him
花上漫长的几天
very slowly in front of everyone here
慢慢地宰了他
over the course of a few very long days.
会议颇有成效  各位
Good meeting, people.
一起让今天成为美好的一天吧
Now let's make today the best today it can be.
对于你在会议中的支持
I'd like to express my sincere thanks
我想表达诚挚的谢意
for your support at the recent confab.
我竭尽我所能保持低调
I was doing my level best to stay fully on the DL,
但有时协调口与脑的神经失效
but sometimes the mouth-brain neuronal connection experience
猝不及防说错了话
is a misfire, and foot met mouth at an unavoidable velocity.
你在屋里说得没错
You were right in there.
你不说  我也会说
If you didn't say it, I would've.
为表示感谢
As a token of my appreciation,
我给你带了我私藏的优质小黄瓜
I brought you some primo cukes from my private stash.
愿你能收下  它象征我
I'd like you to accept these as a sign of my faith
坚信我们能脱离困境的信心[谐音腌黄瓜]
that we will, in fact, find a way out of this pickle.
故意双关的
Pun intended.
谢谢你来一趟
Thanks for stopping by.
等等  那个...
Hold up. It's --
还没干
It's still wet.
抱歉
My apologies.
你自制的吗
You DIY'd these?
对
That's right.
我完全能理解
I fully understand the reasoning
在各种叛变情况下
behind yours truly being prime suspect
怀疑本人是头号嫌疑犯的逻辑
in pretty much any Benedict Arnold type situation.
在此情况下
And in light of that,
我很高兴有你为我殿后
I'm doubly grateful to have you watching my six.
你之前在屋里说得对
You were right back there.
除此之外我什么都没说
I didn't say anything more than that.
你灾变前帮助过弱者吗
You helped the weak before this?
孩子们
Kids.
如果不教他们
You don't show them the way,
他们就会变成渣滓
well, they turn out like garbage.
小混蛋变成大混蛋
Little assholes become great big ones,
所以得教他们
so you show them the way.
成年人也需要
Adults, they need it, too --
政府  法律  宗教  罪孽
the government, laws, religion, guilt.
人生来就是弱者
People are weak.
所有人吗
Everyone?
所有人
Everyone.
你就是弱者
You're weak.
滥杀无辜
Killing the innocent.
对也不对
Right and goddamn wrong.
我的确是弱者  但是"滥杀无辜"
I'm weak, but me "Killing the innocent"?
并不是原因  小加
That ain't why, Gabey.
我们再等一会
We'll wait a little bit longer,
看看我的人能不能缓过来
see if my people can pull it together.
那你为什么是弱者
Why are you weak?
你问错了
That's the wrong question.
应该问我如何弱
It is how I am weak.
事实上  我也很强
You see, the thing is, I am also strong.
所有人都是综合体
Everyone is a mix.
你可以用你的弱点来激发你的长处
You can use your weaknesses to drive your strength,
我显然他妈非常强
and obviously, I am strong as shit.
我占领了这里
I took this place,
这里本来无法无天  只有一群混蛋
and it was a damn free-for-all -- a loose confederation of assholes,
都是一群禽兽
an army made up of gangs of animals,
我将他们整合起来
and I brought it all together.
之前的领袖
The last guy that was in charge,
屁都没管过
he wasn't in charge of shit.
他让人变弱  我不会
He allowed people to be weak. I don't.
我让他们变强  也让这个世界变强
I make them strong, which makes this world strong.
你会明白的  小加
You're gonna see, Gabey.
我会让你成为我新的培养对象
See, I'm gonna make you my new special project.
我会让你也变强
Gonna make you nice and strong, too.
我们要找到属于你的特殊使命
We're gonna find your special purpose.
肯定会的
Hell yes, we are.
我很强
I'm strong.
我杀过人
I've killed.
我当时也在卫星站
I was at the Satellite Station. I was a part of that.
你趁我的人在睡梦中时杀了他们
Then you killed my people while they were sleeping.
看看你  一脸得意的样子
Well, look at you, swinging your dick.
当然了  小加
Sure, Gabe.
那的确很强
That's strong.
但我说的不是那个意思
But that's not what I'm talking about.
告诉我你如何弱了
Tell me how you're weak.
我们可能活不久了
We might be dead soon.
你可能会死
You may be dead.
你不想在此之前忏悔吗
Wouldn't you want to confess before all that happens?
你不想得到赦免吗
Wouldn't you want absolution before that?
宽恕
Forgiveness?
你只要大声地说出真相
Costs you nothing more than saying the truth aloud.
你觉得你没有什么要忏悔的吗
You don't think you have anything to confess?
你所杀的那些人
People you've killed?
我杀的都是该死之人
I haven't killed anyone that didn't need it.
那些被你当做奴隶的工人
The workers you treat like slaves.
这是经济秩序
It's an economy.
有人赢  有人输
Some people win, some people lose,
但没人是奴隶  没人会挨饿
but no one's a slave, no one's going hungry,
在此之前可不是这样
and you couldn't say that before all this.
卡尔跟我们说了你的那些妻子们
Carl told us about your wives.
那些被迫嫁给你的女人们
The women you pressure into marrying you?
那些女士都是自己做出的选择
Every one of those ladies made a choice.
有第一任吗
Was there a first?
在此之前
One before all of this?
那个你答应守护一生
A wife you promised to have and to hold,
不离不弃的结发妻子
forsaking all others?
那个被你谎言欺骗的妻子
One you told that lie to?
露西尔  给我力量
Lucille, give me strength.
好了  小加
All right, Gabe!
没人来救我们
No one's coming for us.
你试过了  试了好几次
You took your shot -- shots.
该走了
It's time to go.
帮我一把
Hey. Give me a hand with this.
好
Yep.
-拿稳了吗  -好了
- Got it? - Yeah.
这些可以派上用场了
We can use these now.
什么
What?
想想吧
Well, think about it.
再也没有神之国了
There ain't no Kingdom no more.
是啊
Yeah.
我们知道接下来该做什么
We know what we got to do.
我们炸开救世堂  让行尸涌进去
We blow open the Sanctuary, let the walkers flood in.
他们会投降的
They'll surrender.
会成功的
It'll be done.
日落前就能结束这一切
Hell, we could end this by sundown.
里面还有工人  不是吗
They have workers in there, right?
还有家人
Families, too.
有吗
Are there?
我们进攻主楼的南面
We'll hit the south side of the main building.
所有工人都住在北面
The workers live in the north side.
他们在行尸来之前就能上楼
They'll be up the stairs before the walkers even get in.
要是他们没上楼呢
What if they don't?
里面有些人并不是战士
There are people in there who aren't fighters.
这样做会改变这点
Doing this could change that.
他们会拿起枪  站在救世军那边
Make them pick up guns and stand by the Saviors.
要是救世军不投降
And if the Saviors don't surrender,
也许所有人都会与我们战斗
maybe everyone fights us.
而我们已经没有神之国相助了
And we don't have the Kingdom anymore.
不能这么做
We're not doing this.
不
No.
是你不能这么做
You ain't doing this.
我们有计划  每个人都要按计划来
There's a plan, and everyone's sticking to it.
并不是所有人
Not everyone.
有不少我们的人牺牲了  瑞克
There's a lot of our people that are dead, Rick.
情况变了  老兄
Things change, man.
这全怪尼根和另一个团体
Negan and that other group, this is on them.
要是有人死了  是他们的错  不是我们的
If people die, it's their fault, not ours.
达里尔  我们不能这么做
Daryl, we can't do this.
我们还要照顾自己的人
And we got our own people to look after.
不能这么做
We're not doing this.
听着  我不会让你这么做的
Hey. I'm not letting you do this.
由不得你
This ain't your choice.
见鬼
Hell.
-达里尔  -起来
- Daryl! - Get up!
我们有计划
There's a plan.
应该执行到底
We got to see it through.
我们得赢
We gotta win.
没错  我们得赢
Yeah, we gotta.
锁喉犯规了  混蛋
Choke hold's illegal, asshole.
嗯  没错
Mm-hmm. Yes, it is.
看来我得走路了
Looks like I'm walking.
没错
Yep.
最后一步结束后我就去和你碰头
I'll meet you when I'm done with the last play.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure about doing it?
我确定
Yeah, I am.
我们有露西尔帮我们抵达救世堂
We have Lucille to help us get to the Sanctuary.
我们有那把枪
We have that gun.
我们应该用上
We should use it.
更重要的是  加百利  我们有彼此
Most importantly, Gabriel, we have each other.
人就是资源
People are a resource.
只要能进去  我们就能活下来
We make it inside, we live.
我们可以冒险一下  抹上内脏
We can take a chance, we can "Gut up,"
假扮行尸  穿过院子
play dead ones across the courtyard.
或者
Or...
我可以直接杀了你  但这不是我想要的
Or I can just kill you, but that is not what I want.
我想要的是和你合作
What I want is for you to work with me.
这就是我想要的全部
That is all I ever want.
我杀过人  但这并不是我最大的罪孽
I've killed before, but that's not my greatest sin.
不是
No.
在灾变伊始  我把我的会众关在了教堂门外
I locked my congregation out of my church when this all just started.
我听着他们死去的声音  我退缩了
I listened to them die... as I cowered.
我辜负了他们
I failed them.
我对不起上帝
I failed God.
每一天
And every day,
我都努力赎罪
I work to lessen that failure,
做一个有作用和有使命的人
to be of service and purpose.
现在我向你保证你会得到宽恕
Now I offer you the assurance of a pardon,
忏悔和赦免
penance, and absolution.
我会跟你走
I will go with you.
我会向你展示  人人平等共同努力
I will show you that working together as equals
是得到恩惠和享有未来的
is the only true way to grace,
唯一正确道路
to a future.
只要你忏悔  我就这样做
I will do this... if you confess.
天啊  小加
Jesus, Gabe.
你做的那事
What you did,
真是可怕  懦弱  没骨气
that is some horrible, cowardly, spineless shit.
但我猜忏悔就该这样  对吧
But I guess that's what a confession's supposed to be, right?
我的第一任妻子是真正的妻子
My first wife was a real wife.
我唯一真正的妻子
My only real wife.
直到死亡拆散我们
Till death did us part.
那是灾变前
It was before this.
我骗了她  出去乱搞
I lied to her, I screwed around on her.
后来她病了
And she was sick.
她走的时候
And when she went...
她走的时候  灾变刚开始
When she went, it was during this.
我对她下不了手
I couldn't put her down.
这就是我如何弱的
That is how I was weak.
这是我要忏悔的事情
That is what I will confess.
因为没错  我们可能等会就死在这了
Because, yeah, maybe we do bite the big one here.
你被宽恕了
You're forgiven.
谢谢
Thanks.
拿着你的枪吧
You can keep your gun.
惨了小加  我们要冒着进嘴巴的风险
Sucks, Gabe, but it looks like we got to risk eating it...
涂上它
...by eating it.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你以前用内脏伪装过吗
You ever done this trick with the guts before?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
都是些腐烂恶臭的内脏
These are putrid, decaying organs,
行尸的血  大小便
dead blood, piss, and shit
在弗吉尼亚州的阳光下暴晒发酵
that have been cooking all day in the Virginian sun.
你们的人没有因此染病的吗
None of your people ?ever gotten sick from this?
我们来自乔治亚州
We're from Georgia.
你们这群幸运的混球
Look at you lucky shits.
我们制造点噪音
Let's make some noise.
见鬼
Oh, damn.
今天应该从我的哨站运送物资
Now, we were due for a delivery today from my place.
侦查员什么都没看到
Spotters haven't seen anything.
是的  运输卡车如果看到情况
Yeah, the transport truck would've turned around,
应该会往回开的
seeing the state of things,
但是路上什么车也没有
but nothing's come up any of the roads.
化工厂哨站不会错过送货的
Chem outpost doesn't miss deliveries.
一定是发生了什么
Something happened.
那个瑞克动手了
That Rick guy happened.
我们的哨站被袭击了...
Our outposts are getting hit while --
怎么了
What is it?
他们上楼了
They're coming up the stairs.
行尸吗
Walkers?
工人
The workers.
他们说不怕吃枪子
They said we'd have to shoot them.
工人只能待在一楼
Workers are designated to stay on the ground level.
妈呀
Jesus Christ.
工人的特定活动区域
Specifically, their activity is constrained
只有工厂车间和室外庭园
to the factory floor and the outdoor gardens.
下面太热了
It's too hot down there.
而且我们绝不会去外面
And we sure as hell ain't going outside.
你们什么时候修好电机
When you gonna fix the power?
不需要修
It doesn't need fixing.
我们在节省燃料
We're conserving fuel.
这是同舟共济
Mm? It's a shared sacrifice.
你们现在开始同舟共济了
Oh. You're sharing now.
这种语气我忍不了
That sort of tone is not gonna work for me. - Hey,
大家听好
everyone, everyone!
我们能挺过去的
Look, we're gonna get through this.
好吗  我们只是需要更多时间
Okay? We just need some more time.
我们需要更多水
We need some more water!
下面有老人孩子
There are young people, old people!
水也要定量分配
We're rationing that out, too.
我们工作  你们保护我们
We work, you protect us.
这是说好的
That was the deal.
-本该是这样的  -对啊
- That's how it was supposed to work. - Yeah.
我们需要水
We need water!
你们有救我们出去的计划吗
Do you have a plan for getting us out?!
你们听到首领的话了
You heard the man!
你们都必须回车间
You all need to get back to the factory floor.
尼根在哪
Where's Negan?
他死了吗
Is he dead?
回答问题
Answer the question.
所有人立刻回车间
Everyone has to return to the factory floor now!
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我要在这点上纠正你
I need to correct you on that point.
-尼根在哪  -有枪
- Where's Negan?! - Gun!
我是尼根
I am Negan!
还有人想吃枪子吗
Anyone else want a bullet?
还有人吗
Anyone?
瑞吉娜
Ah, Regina.
你为什么要这样做
Now, why'd you have to go and do that?
我猜你们很多人都以为我死了
I am guessing that a lot of you fine folks thought I was dead,
被咬碎吞了  死不见尸
chewed up, never to be crapped out again.
我提醒一下你们我他妈是谁
Well, here's a little refresher on who the hell I am.
我穿皮夹克  持露西尔
I wear a leather jacket, I have Lucille,
有金刚不坏之蛋
and my nutsack is made of steel.
没享完福之前  我绝不会轻易死去
I am not dying until I am damn good and ready.
现在  失陪了
Now, if you'll all excuse me,
我急需吃个三明治  冲个澡
I am in deep need of a sandwich, a shower,
享受一下弗兰基在旧金山学的
and some of that, uh, wilting lion orchid
垂狮兰泰式深层组织按摩
deep-tissue shit that Frankie learned in San Francisco.
见鬼  我说不定会同时做
Hell, I might do it all at once.
但是在那之后  我们要处理一些严肃的事
But after that, we have some serious business to attend to.
比如跟我的得力手下谈谈
Like talking to my right-hand man.
我们必须搞清楚
You see, we got to figure out
为什么会发生这种事
how all this could've happened like it happened.
然后
And then...
我们要继续做我们一直做的事
Well, and then we're gonna get back doing what we have always done.
我们要拯救人们
We will save people.
谢谢你  尼根  感谢上帝有你
Thank you, Negan. Thank God for you.
这就是我在这里的原因
And that is why I am here.
先生们  温柔地带他去二号牢房
Gentlemen, gently take him to number 2.
温柔地
Gently.
好消息是  我搞清楚了
Good news is, I figured out
那混蛋的枪是从哪来的
where that asshole's gun came from.
坏消息呢
And the bad news?
枪是我们的
They're ours.
从武器库偷的
Stolen from the armory.
工人不可能在我们眼皮底下偷这么多枪
A worker couldn't have gotten this many guns without us knowing about it.
他们一把都偷不走
They couldn't have got one.
没错  是自己人干的  现在依然在干
No, one of our own did this -- is doing this, right now.
告诉我该怎么揪出他  西蒙
Tell me how we find him, Simon.
我们查出军火的失窃时间
We...find when the munitions went missing.
通过这个  查出失窃过程
Through that, we get an idea of the how,
但愿能牵出内鬼是谁
which hopefully leads us right to who.
但先查时间
But we start with when.
机灵鬼博士
Dr. Smartypants.
有个很大的机遇
Big, big chance here.
你要是能解决了外面臭烘烘的行尸
You solve this thing with the bad-smelling convention outside,
我会让你非常非常开心的
I will make you very, very happy.
但即使你尽了全力
But even if you try your best
而我也知道你尽了全力
and I know you try your best
依然想不出什么方法
but you don't figure something out...
我向你保证  我会给你个痛快
I assure you, I will kill you quickly
省的你看到食物和水耗尽后
so you don't have to see all the awful, horrific things
这里变成恐怖的人间地狱
that are gonna go down here when we run out of food and water.
我想说的是
What I'm saying...
不管怎样  我都会帮你
is that I got your back either way.
你会帮我吗
You got mine?
加百利  我是尤金·伯特
Gabriel, it's Eugene Porter.
尤金·伯特博士
Dr. Eugene Porter here.
我们曾是邻居  旅伴
We were, uh...neighbors, traveling companions.
我们一起吃过狗肉  所以
We've eaten dog together, so...
我猜也算是一辈子的交情
I imagine that joins us in some manner for life.
我是来正式欢迎你来到救世堂的
I'm here to formally welcome you to the Sanctuary.
因为目前被围  热出来的痱子
In our current state of siege, the prickly heat alone
可能会导致你对这里留下坏印象
might be enough to turn you off the place,
所以我觉得自己有责任
so I took it upon myself
给你带来一些欢迎物品
to...bring you some welcome-wagon items
希望能减轻你的痛苦
in hopes of providing some relief.
加百利
Gabriel?
你必须立刻看卡森医生2.0
You need to see Dr. Carson 2.0 A.S.A.P.
是的
I d-- I do.
这就是我在这里的原因
That's why I'm here. That's why --
这就是我们在这里的原因
It's the reason we're here, I think.
我觉得...
I think it's...
卡森...是玛姬的医生
Carson...is Maggie's doctor.
我们必须救他出去
W-We have to get him out of here.
We have to get him out of here.
我们必须救他...
We have to get him out of...